SHABAB HASNAT TOHA

linkedin.com/in/shababtoha github.com/shababtoha

SUMMARY

Aspiring software engineer offering **3 years of professional experience** building customer-focused web and mobile apps and leading sub-teams. Excited to work with distributed algorithms & design scalable products hand on. Tech I have worked With

-Java (Android and & J2EE, Spring) -JS (Angular, React, jQuery, Node, TypeScript, RxJs) -C/C++ (GCC)

-Python (Django) -HTML, CSS, Bootstrap -Issue Tracker(Jira)

-Message Queue(RabbitMQ) -DMBS (MSSQL, MySQL, Mongo, Oracle, PostgreSQL)

-Version Control (Git)

EMPLOYMENT

<u>Software Engineer</u> <u>Enosis Solutions</u> <u>March 2019 – Present</u>
WorkStraight Jan 2022 – Present

A work order management application that securely creates, receives, and tracks work requests from the team, customers, or outside contractors.

- Lead a sub-team of 2 members - Did all the necessary R&D

- Converted Existing Website form PERL to .NET and Angular - Improved UI / UX

- Reduce page loading time by implementing cache. 30% faster - Optimized database queries than existing application

Tip Technologies Mar 2019 – Dec 2022

A Quality Management Software (QMS) that ensures industry leaders control compliance and effectively manage quality with their supply chain

Background process service

-Integrated our application with 3rd party ERP services -Implemented Message queuing to (Oracle, SAP, DELTEK) -Sync data 50% faster

- -Implemented both way data sync with webhook
- -Designed and implemented REST API to outside access
- DB-Updater
 - -Built an internal tool to compare 2 databases
- Periodically sync databases
- -Run database scripts manually with the application
- -Log comparison summary and show them on charts.

• Video Conference

- -Bult an internal video conference tool without any third-party integration
- -Included real-time non-persistent chat service

Software Engineer, Intern

Mukto Software Ltd

Dec 2017 - Oct 2018

- Designed Responsive webpages using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, and JavaScript
- · Gathered knowledge on Backend development using Node.js, Express and MongoDB
- Learned and built websites using Django, Django Rest Framework and React
- Developed Wikipedia viewer using JavaScript with Wikipedia API where users can search articles

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Node-React-Messenger: A real-time chatting application using React, Node.js, GraphQL, and PostgreSQL
- **Mist Computer Club**: Website for our University computer club whose main feature is an online judge to arrange programming contests.

EDUCATION

Dhaka Bangladesh

Military Institute of Science and Technology

Feb 2015 - Dec 2019

- · B. Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering
- Secretary and competitive programming mentor of MIST Computer Club